> > Jem Young: 现在我们要谈的是集装箱。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Now we're
gonna talk about containers.
容器很迷人
Containers are fascinating.
他们正在改变服务器的状况
They are changing
the landscape of servers and
我们对建筑结构的思考方式
the way we think about how
to structure architecture.
刚才我们说过建筑的问题比我们想象的要多
A little bit ago we talked about how the
architecture matters more than we think
作为高级工程师，我们需要思考的是建筑。
and as senior engineers there something
we need to think about is architecture.
作为高级的全堆工程师们，我们想仔细想想
And as senior full stack engineers,
we want to think carefully about how
我们的应用程序是结构化的，就像他们在服务器上的生活一样。
our applications are structured,
as in how they live on the server.
所以我们在讨论集装箱因为他们改变了
So we're talking about containers because
they have been changing the game across
这条网景
the net landscape.
让我们从一个微型服务开始。
Let's start with a micro service.
有人对微型服务有什么好的定义，谁不是 Sam 。
Does anybody have a good definition,
who's not Sam, of a micro service.
就像扔了它听起来像什么
Like throw it out What does it sound like?
>> off 屏幕女性: 仅完成一个任务的服务 ?
&gt;&gt; off screen female: A service
that only completes one task?
> > Jem Young: 是的，我喜欢
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah, I like that.
这是一个很小很小的服务
It's a teeny tiny service.
如果我们谈论微型服务
If we talk about microservices,
我们谈论的是一种松散连接的服务架构。
we talk about an architecture
of loosely connected services.
这是一种错误的错误因为仅仅因为它是一个微型服务
It's kind of a misnomer because
just because it's a microservice
并不代表它很小巧轻便
doesn't mean it's really small and
lightweight.
所以我喜欢你我喜欢你的定义只做一件事
So I like what you I like your definition
of its it only does one thing because
那是对微型服务的更清晰的定义
that's a better definition
of a microservice.
它只做一件事
It only does one thing.
微服务架构的反面是什么 ?
What's the opposite of
micro service architecture?
嗯。
Yes.
> > 屏幕雌性: 巨石?
&gt;&gt; off screen female: A monolith?
>> Jem Young: 单块。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: A monolith.
嗯。
Yes.
这是一个能做一切的应用。
That is one app that does everything.
历史上是 Java 应用程序或节点应用程序或
Historically that's been a Java
application or a node application or
Python 和 Django，类似的，都是一个应用程序。
Python with Django, something like that,
where it's all one application.
我们说要搬家的时候就有勾销
There are trade offs we make
when we talk about moving to
微服务与巨石之间的关系
microservices versus a monolith.
一个巨石的好处是
The good thing about a monolith is that.
你都用同样的语言
You're all using the same language.
所以如果你雇佣一堆 Python 人，我们都是在为 Python工作。
So if you hire a bunch of Python people,
we're all working in Python.
他们不是分开的服务
They're not separate services.
安全更新从 Python 2 迁移到 Python 3
Security updates moving,
migrating from Python two to Python three,
你一次都能做到
you can do it all at one time.
因为没有太多的空间，所以它能让维修变得更容易些
And it actually makes maintenance a little
bit easier because you don't have a lot of
不同的语言和服务相互交谈。
disparate languages and
services talking to each other.
这只是一个申请
It's just one application.
>> Jem Young: 单块的下面是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: What is
the downside of a monolith?
> > 屏幕雌性 : 更难改变和自动操作。
&gt;&gt; off screen female: It's just harder
to make changes and automate things.
你必须立刻把一切都推过去
You have to push everything all at once.
>> Jem Young: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah.
>> 屏幕上的男士: 你可以摆脱一切
&gt;&gt; off screen male: You can get
away from having everything
与微服务松散耦合。
loosely coupled with microservices.
你可以通过设计保证一切都独立。
You can kinda by design guarantee
that everything is independent.
有了巨石你就可以变成一个
And with a monolith, you can fall
into the pattern of having one
事物会影响到其他事物并紧密结合
thing affect multiple other things and
it's tightly coupled.
你可以打碎东西，并产生意想不到的后果。
And you can break things and
have unintended consequences.
> > Jem Young: 是的，你长的样子。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah,
it's exactly what you look like.
你宁愿有一帮比较容易维护的小房子吗
Would you rather have a bunch of tiny
houses that are easier to maintain?
还是你宁愿有一栋巨大的建筑
Or would you rather have
one giant building?
那得看情况了
It depends.
我不是来告诉你的你有一个
I won't be here to tell you,
you've one or the other.
我只是来告诉你不同类型的
I'm just here to tell you
about the different types,
我不想把它政治化太多
I don't wanna politicize it too much.
>> 禁用屏幕男性: 您谈到升级和
&gt;&gt; off screen male: You
talked about upgrades and
保护你安全的东西
keeping you stuff upgraded for security.
如果你要升级包就更难了
That's harder with the monolith
if you are upgrading packages,
您必须在整个代码库中进行升级。
you have to upgrade it
across the entire code base.
那就更难了不然就更难了
Versus little, or it can be harder.
那得看情况了
It depends.
>> Jem Young: 这要看情况。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: It depends.
所以是和不，不是一个尺码都适合
So yes and no, it's not a one size
fits all and anybody that says
微服务比 monolith 更好， monolith 优于微服务。
microservices are better than monolith,
monolith's better than microservice.
他们都错了因为这真的取决于你的申请
They're both wrong because it
really depends on your application,
你的公司结构，你有什么类型的工程师，之类的。
how your company structured, what type
of engineers you have, things like that.
就应用程序而言，是，升级微服务可能更容易
As far as applications go, yeah, it might
be easier to upgrade a microservice
因为您可以一次升级一次。
because you can upgrade
them one at a time.
但另一方面你要做的升级都要做
But at the other hand, you have all
the upgrades you have to do for
每一个微型服务
every single microservice.
您需要执行以下操作的所有安全补丁
You have all the security
patches you need to do for
每个微服务与一座巨石之间的关系
every single microservice
versus a monolith.
你做一次就在一起了
You do it one time and it's all together.
它可能比较麻烦，但更容易做到一次。
It can be more cumbersome but
it's easier to do all at once.
再一次，这个整个容器，微型服务的单块建筑，
So again, this whole container,
microservice monolith architecture,
那得看情况了
it depends.
它取决于用例，它取决于贵公司的构建。
It depends on use case,
it depends on your company's builds.
但微型服务主要基于这个概念，现在称为容器，
But microservices are largely built on
this concept now called containers,
我们会在第二个方面谈
which we'll talk about in a second.
但我可以说一些微型服务，因为我在 Netflix工作。
But I can speak a little bit about
microservices because I work at Netflix.
这不像，这是我们内部基础设施的一个例子。
This is not like, this is an example
of our internal infrastructure.
但这些都是假名字
But these are fake names, obviously.
如果你知道一艘游艇是什么，它就不会告诉你任何东西。
It wouldn't tell you anything,
if you knew what a field craft was.
这很酷野外的手艺让我听起来像个间谍
That's pretty cool, field craft,
makes me sound like a spy.
但 Netflix 是其中之一，我不会说其中一位领导人。
But Netflix is one of,
I won't say one of the leaders.
这让我听起来像是在用自己的喇叭
It makes me sound like
I'm tooting my own horn.
但我们是微型服务的 [LAUGH] 领导人之一。
But we are one of the [LAUGH]
leaders in microservices.
我们都相信，这对我们的用例更有效。
It's something we all believe, that
it's more efficient for our use cases.
例如，我在 UI 团队中工作。
For instance, I work on the UI team.
所以我就住在这里
So I live about here.
因为我不太在边缘
Because I'm not quite at the edge gateway.
他是我们开放的源负载均衡器之一
That would be Zuul,
one of our open source Load balancers,
代理，做很多事情。
proxies, does lots of things.
这就来了我在这儿工作
That would be about here coming in and
I work about about here.
所以我住的是 UI 层
So I live on the UI layer, but
这就是高复杂度的高 [ LAUGH] 。
behind that is this high
[LAUGH] mess of complexity.
但好事是我的团队在节点堆栈中运行 React 。
But the good thing is my team
runs React in a Node stack.
其他人员运行 Java，其他人员运行 Groovy ，这是 Java 的风格。
Other people run Java, other people
run Groovy, which is a flavor of Java.
其他人运行 PHP，有些人以 Python 运行。
Other people run PHP,
some people run in Python.
但这些团队中的每一个都能维持自己的堆栈。
But every one of these teams
can maintain their own stack.
只要我们坚持共同的 API ，你就可以为所欲为。
And as long as we maintain that common
API, you can kind of do whatever you want.
这就是自由的责任。
It very much lives up to
that freedom responsibility.
维护自己的堆栈，维护自己的体系结构。
You maintain your own stack,
you maintain your own architecture.
如果你的团队就像世界上最伟大的鲁斯特程序员
And if your team is like the world's
greatest Rust programmers, write your
在鲁斯特服役但我不需要知道它是怎么运作的
service in Rust, which will be really but
I don't need to know how it works.
这就是微型服务架构的好处。
That's the benefit of
the microservice architecture.
下面是这个复杂性，而不是这里的一个东西，
The downside is look at this
complexity instead of one thing here,
就是这个巨大的 Java 应用或者类似的东西
which is this giant Java app or
something like that.
我们有其他的应用需要相互沟通
We have all these other apps that
need to talk to each other and
保持联系和类似的事情，我们用这个概念来做这个。
maintain connections and things like that,
and we do this with this concept called.
一个容器
A container.
你觉得集装箱是什么
Now what do you think a container is?
>> Jem Young: 是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes.
>> 关闭屏幕男性: 这是在环境中对代码进行分区的方法
&gt;&gt; off screen male: It's a way of
partitioning your code in an environment
它可以运行，只需要包含必需的组件。
that it can run in, with only
the necessary components included.
> > Jem Young: 是的，我问你，还有点更难的问题。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes, so I'll ask you,
and even a bit harder question.
容器和虚拟机有什么区别 ?
What's the difference between
a container and a virtual machine?
>> off screen : 虚拟机是整个操作系统模拟机器。
&gt;&gt; off screen male: A virtual machine
is a whole OS simulating machine.
容器可以减轻重量。
A container can be lighter weight.
>> Jem Young: 正是这样，这才是正确的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Precisely,
that's exactly right.
虚拟机具有整个操作系统。
Virtual machines have
an entire operating system.
在微型服务架构的旧日里
So in the old days of
the microservice architecture,
我要像现在这样运行一个 Ubuntu 版本。
I would have to run a version of
Ubuntu like we're running now.
然后我就会跑了
And then I'd run Node.
如果我想为我的数据库再运行一次微型服务
And then if I wanna run another
microservice for my database,
我会用另一个版本的 Node 来运行 Fedora 或 Ubuntu 。
I'd run Fedora or
Ubuntu with another version of Node.
那是以前的日子
And that was the old days.
这看起来挺不错的，你很喜欢，对，有点重。
That seemed pretty good, cuz you're like
well, yeah that's a little bit heavy.
但至少现在每个服务都有自己的操作系统
But at least now every service
has its own operating system and
然后，他们只能通过已知的 API 来与其他服务进行对话。
then they can only talk to
other services over known APIs.
容器采用该概念，并触发更多信息。
Containers take that concept and
trigger down even more.
而不是在操作系统上运行
Instead of running out
on an operating system,
就像每个集装箱都有自己的操作系统
like every container has
its own operating system,
我们只运行它所需要的一组库，而仅运行其他的库。
we just run just the set of libraries that
it needs, and only that, nothing else.
这就是一个容器。
And that's what a container is.
容器在当今的环境中强大，我们只能使用它们
Containers are powerful in the way that
they are today and we can only use them
因为云计算和我们所取得的进步
because of cloud computing and
the advances that we've made.
我们在管理程序上取得进展
We've made advances in the hypervisor,
这就是控制其他进程的过程，以及它们之间的对话方式。
that is the process that controls other
processes, how they talk to each other.
这就是我们现在的工作方式。
And that's how we're working right now.
这就是我们的服务器运行和运行的方式，这是我们可以进行隔离处理的事实。
That's how our servers up and running, is
the fact that we can do process isolation.
但我要在这小小的服务器上运行
But I'm running on this tiny,
tiny, tiny sliver of the server.
老实说，你们都可以和我在同一个服务器上跑步，我不知道。
And honestly, you all can be running on
the same server as me, I have no idea.
因为我们有流程隔离，系统管理程序很不错
Because we have process isolation and the
hypervisor is really good at segmenting
我们的资源是一体的
our resources to one or the other.
当我们建立在这个之上的时候，我们就有了这个容器的概念。
When we build on top of that,
we have this idea of containers.
而不是 VPS ，我们可以放大甚至更多地放大
So instead of the VPS, we can zoom in
even more and we take that concept of
一个服务器，我们把它细分为不同的部分。
a server and we just segment that
out into different sections.
但每一节都只有它自己的图书馆，它拥有自己的资源。
But every section only has it's
own libraries, it's own resources.
它不一定知道它所开启的操作系统。
It doesn't necessarily even know about
the operating system that it's on.
它才不管呢
It doesn't care.
这是包装器的内容，类似于编排层。
That's what the wrapper is for,
something like the orchestration layer.
怎么了
Yes?
> > 脱网男: 我想说，这有点像不同，但是
&gt;&gt; off screen male: I was gonna say,
it's kind of like the difference, but
树在颤抖
tree shaking.
其中您仅包含实际使用的功能，
Where you only include the functionality
that you actually use,
包括整个图书馆
versus including the entire library.
>> Jem Young: 是的，或者我喜欢说的是哥伦布的做法。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yes exactly, or as I like
to say, the Columbo way of doing it.
只是事实而已
Just the facts.
这正是它需要的
It's just what it needs.
所以不要把整个操作系统都包括在每一个
So rather than including an entire
operating system on every single
应用程序，我们只包括它需要的库。
application, we'll just include
the libraries that it needs.
>> Jem Young: 这是以前的日子。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: This was the old days.
这将是虚拟机。
This would be a virtual machine.
这可能是我们的服务器
This could be our server.
其实现在离我们的服务器很近
Actually it's pretty close
to our server right now.
我们有 NodeJS 正在运行 Nginx 正在运行
We have NodeJS running,
we have Nginx running.
稍后，我将了解如何安装 MySQL。
We later I'll go over
how to install MySQL.
不会太多，但我们可以运行 Python。
Won't do too much with it,
but we can run Python.
这是以前的做法。
This was the old way of doing it.
容器是这样的。
Containers are something like this.
它还是一台服务器。
It's still one server.
但现在它是它自己的微型服务器。
But now this is kind of
its own micro server.
并且 MySQL 数据库未在其自己的微型服务器， Nginx等上运行。
And the MySQL database isn't running on
its own microserver, Nginx, etc., etc.
他们只拥有他们需要的图书馆。
And they only have
the libraries that they need.
为甚么会有这种好处呢 ?
Why is this beneficial?
比如这事的威力
Like what's powerful about this.
我们现在没有在每个应用程序上运行整个操作系统，但是
We're not running an entire operating
system on every single application now but
我们还能做些什么
what's something we can
do even more when we're
控制单个容器本身。
controlling the individual
containers itself.
>> off screen male: 运行其中的几个。
&gt;&gt; off screen male: Run several of them.
几份
Several copies.
> > Jem Young: 是的，你可以，但我们也能做虚拟机。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah no, you can, but
we can do that virtual machines too.
但你在正确的轨道上
But you're on the right track.
还有别的吗
What else?
>> Jem Young: 他们是。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: They are.
是的，速度更快。
Yes, they are faster.
但是当我们想到集装箱的时候，我们大概没有想到一个好处
But there's one benefit we probably don't
think of when we think of containers
>> 屏幕阳性 : 静态分析。
&gt;&gt; off screen male: Static analysis.
>> Jem Young: 不，你的意思是什么 ?
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: No,
what do you mean by that?
>> 禁用屏幕男性: 静态分析允许您通过图形跟踪
&gt;&gt; off screen male: Static analysis allows
you to trace through the graph of what
依赖树是并确定要包含的内容，要包括的内容。
the dependency tree is and figure out
what to include, what to exclude.
不仅减少了资源，也减少了内存。
Reduces not just resources,
in terms of processing but also memory.
>> Jem Young: 是的。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Yeah.
更进一步，如果我们知道，因为你是绝对正确的。
Take that idea further, if we know,
because you're you're absolutely right.
我不知道我是否称它为静态分析，但对每一个数据的分析
I don't know if I call it static analysis
as much but the analysis of what every
单一的应用是在做而不是作为一个整体，我必须要运行我的负载，
single application is doing rather than
as a whole, I have to run my load,
运行 topper 其他命令以查看类似的情况，
run topper other commands to see like,
究竟是什么容器在做什么，或者一个过程正在做什么。
what exactly what containers doing,
or what a process is doing.
当我把它装在容器里的时候
When I have it in container.
我知道它在干什么
I know precisely what it's doing.
通过这样做，我可以限制
And by doing that I can limit
the amount of resources that have given
容器有，我可以向上扩展和缩小的速度更快。
container has, and I can scale up and
scale down much faster.
例如，如果我运行 Python Web 服务器，那么它将被阻塞。
For instance, if I run a Python
web server it's gonna be blocking.
我们之前谈到了拦截请求，如果我请求一个真正慢的数据库
We talked about blocking request earlier,
where if I request a really slow database
或者类似的问题它会阻塞所有其他的请求
query or something like that, it's gonna
block all the other requests coming in
除非我有一些合用的东西但那将会拖慢一切
unless I have some sort of pooling enabled
but that'll slow down everything else.
但如果我想限制 Python 可以使用的资源呢 ?
But what if I want to just limit
the resources that Python can use?
我想把它们分配给节点或者类似的东西。
And I want to allocate them in Node or
something like that.
我可以更严格地控制在我的服务器上发生的事情。
I can more tightly control
what's happening on my server.
既然它是自己的服务器，我可以控制它。
And since it's kind of its own server
in a way, and I can control that.
这真的很强大。
And that's really, really powerful.
而这一权力的一部分，我将会谈论更多的容器，
And part of that power, I'll talk about
the benefits even more of containers,
但这权力的一部分就像你们都说的那样你可以把它滚出去
but part of that power is like you all
were saying, you can roll these out much,
速度更快
much faster.
启动时间更快，因为我没有启动整个操作
The startup time is much faster because
I'm not starting an entire operating
系统，我必须安装。
system, that I have to install.
我需要执行无人照管的升级。
I need to run unattended upgrades.
我需要在每台服务器和所有这些东西上安装 Nginx 。
I need to install Nginx on every
single server and all these things.
我可以做图书馆，我可以在一段时间内分发。
I can just run the library, and
I can distribute these over time.
另一个好处是我可以更新我的节点应用程序，
The other benefit is I can make
updates to my node application,
我的 Python 应用程序，甚至不知道它的其他服务。
my Python application without the other
services even knowing about it.
因此，我可以控制单个转出，而不是转出整个服务器
So I can control the individual rollouts
rather than rolling out entire servers
花了很多时间才能上到下
which take a lot of time to take up and
take down.
> > Jem Young: 我们已经获得了一些好处，但它们很轻。
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: And we hit on some of the
benefits already but they're lightweight.
这只是事实
It's just the facts.
它只是它需要的东西。
It's only the things that it needs.
他们是便携的
They're portable.
在这种情况下，我可以创建节点应用程序，
In that case,
I can create a Node application,
把它装在容器里放在我想要的任何地方
wrap it in container and
put it anywhere I want.
不管操作系统是什么，不管它是什么，
And it doesn't matter what the operating
system is that point, it doesn't care,
因为有一个层处理与操作系统的交互。
because there's a layer that handles that
interaction with the operating system.
所以如果我想，我可以写 Node 应用程序，在 Windows 上运行，运行
So if I want, I can write a Node
application, run it on Windows, run it on
我的 Mac 电脑然后在 Ubuntu 上运行它也会运行
my Mac computer and then run it on Ubuntu,
and it's all going to run the same,
与虚拟机非常相似，但没有操作系统开销。
very similar to a virtual machine but
without the operating system overhead.
坦白说，微型服务的发展更容易，因为它不是巨石。
Honestly, microservices are easier for
development because it's not a monolith.
应用程序是，但就像你说的，安娜，它只做一件事。
The application is, but like you're
saying, Anna, it only does one thing.
而且它也做得很好。
And it does one thing well.
这就说明了发生了什么更简单的事情。
That makes reasoning about
what's happening much simpler.
他们更容易管理
They're easier to manage.
我应该给你个星号
I should put an asterisk by this.
正如您之前看到的那样， >> Jem Young: 更容易
As you saw before with the,
&gt;&gt; Jem Young: Easier to
管理是完全相对的。
manage is totally relative.
有人会说，在一个大的教派里，这个比较难管理，我说的比较容易
Some might say this is harder to manage in
one big sect I might say it's easier to
管理。
manage.
因为他们比较容易管理因为它只做一件事
In mind they're easier to manage
because it's only doing one thing and
这道理很合理他们肯定会更快地
that makes rational sense and they're
certain times it's gonna much faster cuz
就不会有什么靴子了
there is no boot up time anymore certain.
完全是 [INAUDIBLE] 把一些文件复制到运行。
It's just literally [INAUDIBLE] just
copying some files over and hitting run.
它真正做的是将应用程序与基础架构分离。
And what it really does is decouples
the application from the infrastructure.
切换到 Ubuntu 20 还是 Fedora ， Red Hat ， Debian 或者 Debian
It doesn't matter if we switch to Ubuntu
20 or Fedora or Red Hat or Debian or
就像这样
something like that.
应用程序不重要，我作为一个开发者，我不在乎。
The application doesn't matter and
me as a developer, I don't care.
反正不影响我的申请，因为有
It doesn't affect my application
anyway because there's
一个能推断出的层
a layer that does that inferring.
这个解释容器我发现有些人喜欢把它们挂在他们的位置上
That explain containers I find people like
get hung up a little bit on them, and
他们把它们与虚拟机和类似的虚拟机以及所有这些东西混淆
they confuse them with virtual machines
and like monoliths and all that stuff.